Ariel Herman

Frontend software engineer with a passion for organized code and empathetic, user-focused design. Experience in Ruby and JavaScript based programming. Strong background in e-commerce, retail fashion, and customer service. Highly skilled in managing product lifecycles and diverse stakeholders, and delivering experiential products that build brand loyalty.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript ES6+, React/Redux, Ruby, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, Typescript, CI/CD tools, Enzyme, React Testing Library, AWS, Figma

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Glossier

Engineer 2 Montréal, QC (October 2019 - Present)
Engineer 1 New York, NY (May 2019 - October 2019)
Junior Engineer New York, NY (July 2018 - May 2019)

- ► Overhauled product pages and reviews, partnering with distributed design, product, data, UX, and marketing stakeholders on a full migration to the React framework, coupled with a mobile-first redesign and iterative AB testing using Agile development. This drove +10.51% CVR among users who viewed a product page and reduced latency on this key mid-funnel surface.
- Initiated Glossier's CSS-in-JS component-based design system, including a sitewide flex-based custom grid layout, to boost developer delivery speed, reduce CSS bundle size, and promote a shared language between engineering and design teams
- ► Project-managed and developed technical implementation for a content-manageable sitewide promotion UI experience, used to message our annual Black Friday Weekend sale
- Expanded documentation for Glossier's E2E AB test implementation, cart and catalog services, and design system
- Served as president for the Women Who Tech employee resource group to spearhead culture and inclusion initiatives. Contributed to the department-wide culture committee to improve employee experience and aid retention.

American Airlines

International Flight Attendant New York, NY (January 2014 - April 2018)

- Collaborated with agents, cabin services, catering, and pilots to improve the company's on-time departure to 69.3%
- Traveled regularly within 20 states and 15 different countries, serving passengers with professionalism and care

Abercrombie & Fitch

Visual Merchandiser Columbus, OH (July 2012 - October 2013)

- Managed presentation of two international flagship stores by utilizing in-house Visual Management Software and weekly planogram updates to inform placement decisions based on sales KPIs
- Designed back-to-school seasonal denim planograms, directed in-store floorset teams to establish presentation standards

Abercrombie & Fitch

Assistant Merchandiser Columbus, OH (October 2011 - July 2012)

- ► Strategized purchase volume, SKU pricing, and managed product lifecycle of 5-10 styles per season within the knit/woven tops category, working to deliver an on-trend product assortment to drive sell-through
- Negotiated with vendors to deliver garments at target FOB pricing at company standard average of 75% IMU per garment

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and Javascript in-person Immersive Program, Jan 2018

University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Arts in East Asian Language and Culture, 2011

VOLUNTEERING

Black Girls CODE New York, NY

Instructed 5th and 6th graders at a "Build A Webpage In A Day" workshop. Built a page to showcase their work

Girls Who Code New York, NY

Presented fundamentals of the engineering job role to summer camp students and led a coding workshop

projectBASTA New York, NY

Motivated students of color who are the first in their family to attend college to increase their networking and elevator pitch skills on the path to job seeking post-graduation in workshops and Q&A sessions